EXPERIENCE

Sep 2018 - Present

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Sisal Entertainment SPA, Milano

Working with the developing team in the mobile betting field. Use of ReactJS to implement new functionalities.

Jun 2018

GUEST LECTURER

ASICT developers training, Politecnico di Milano

Five lectures about the UX design process for the Public Administration Services with the prof. Thimoty Barbieri.

Oct 2015 - Aug 2016

COMMUNICATION SPECIALIST

CityHub Srls, Bergamo

Brand identity and graphics(web and print).

Social media, website and App management. Event planning.

Communication with clients. Photography and post-production.

Managing the Online booking system.

May 2013 - Sep 2013

INTERNSHIP @ THE DESIGN DEPARTMENT

Dep. INDACO, Politecnico di Milano, Milano

Project: "Leonardo, the waters and the rice".

Promoted by: "The agency for the development
of Vigevano's territory". Design of map based elements.

INTERNATIONAL EXPERIENCE

2016 - 2018 STARTUP PROTOTYPING

USA - Italy

Feb 2012 - Jul 2012 EXCHANGE

EXCHANGE STUDENT

QUT, Brisbane(AU)

Aug 2006 - Jul 2007

EXCHANGE STUDENT

Rochester, MI(USA)

ABOUT ME

I love discovering new things.
I believe that "the less you do, the less you'd do"
and this is why I am always active,
trying to improve myself, pushed by a constant curiosity.

My international experience and education enriched my graphic knowledge, for web and print, and increased my awareness of it as a powerful mean of communication, essential within a very competitive digital reality.

After a Master in coding I embraced a career in Front End Development.

- Bergamo, Italy 16/01/1989
- - be.net/francescaschiro
- github.com/francescaSchiro

+39 340 82 66 052



FRANCESCA SCHIRO

Communication & Graphic Designer Front End Developer | UX UI

HARD SKILLS

SOFT SKILLS

Illustrator Re
Photoshop
InDesign
Sketch
InVision C
English
HTML / CSS

Resourcefulness

Teamwork

Determination

Communication

Creativity

Flexibility

Problem solving

EDUCATION

Apr 2018 - Jul 2018
CODEMASTER

TAG Innovation School, Milano

Oct 2011 - Dec 2014

MASTER'S DEGREE IN

COMMUNICATION DESIGN

Politecnico di Milano, Milano

Mar 2013 - May 2013

DIGITAL MAGAZINE WORKSHOP

CFP Bauer, Milano

Oct 2008 - Jul 2011

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN

COMMUNICATION DESIGN

Politecnico di Milano, Milano

Sep 2003 - Jul 2008

HIGH SCHOOL DEGREE

Liceo Scientifico L.Mascheroni, Bergamo

In compliance with the Italian Legislative Decree no. 196 dated 30/06/2003 and EU GDPR (2016/679), I hereby authorize you to use and process my personal details contained in this document

















JS

React